Rúben Aguiar

Problem solver at heart. Passionate about good solutions and good people.

🖂 r.aguiar9080@gmail.com | 🗘 raguiar9080 | 🏕 fractalman.xyz | in raguiar9080 | 📞 +351 966 233 545

Relevant Skills

Scala

5 years experience in Software Engineering, Product oriented development and incident response. Effective communicator, Backend specialist and ML enthusiast with Fullstack and DevOps capabilities and experience. Firm believer in teamwork. My goal is to bring positive change to the world.

DeepLearning AWS Erlang Tensorflow

PostareSOL Rubv

Python Kubernetes Redis Elixir **Terraform** Kafka Javascript Docker Cassandra

Experience ___

Triggerise Porto, Portugal

BACKEND ENGINEER TEAM LEAD October 2020 - Current

· Alongside backend engineer responsibilities, increased focus on product development and vision, recruitment, team mentoring and cross team collaboration. Ownership of the platform operating in multiple countries around the globe: USA, India, Kenya, Ethiopia among others. Main responsible for incident responses requiring technical capabilities.

Triggerise Porto, Portugal

BACKEND ENGINEER

February 2019 - October 2020

• Member of the backend team responsible for the development of the core product. Focus on maintaining and developing new features to power an event-driven platform that operates in several countries around the globe. Platform consists of a front-end for power users, internal and public facing APIs and the backend engine. Performed work on all components including DevOps and SysAdmin tasks when necessary. Main technologies used include: Scala, Ruby, PostgreSQL, Redis, AWS, Salt.

Smarkets London, United Kingdom

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

October 2014 - February 2017

· Main responsibilities were to maintain, improve and extend the Backend of a peer to peer betting exchange handling several thousand concurrent Websocket connections and requests per second. Resilience, throughput and sub millisecond latency were main focuses, which resulted in a major refactor towards a no single point of failure architecture. Frontend, DevOps and SysAdmin tasks executed when necessary. Worked on a small sized team, which over time developed into a multi-team flat hierarchy. Highly invested in company culture through recruitment, team building activities and assuming responsibility for the study and rework of several company-wide policies and guidelines. Main technologies used include Erlang, Python, Kafka, React, PostgreSQL.

AKI Vila Nova de Gaia, Portugal

BARISTA - PART-TIME 2010 - 2014

• Performed several tasks ranging from Costumer Service to Cashier.

Education

Coursera Online

DEEP LEARNING SPECIALIZATION

March 2021 - April 2021

· Completed all five courses of the DeepLearning Specialization. This Specialization focuses on building network architectures such as Convolutional Neural Networks, Recurrent Neural Networks, LSTMs, Transformers, and learning strategies such as Dropout, Batch-Norm, Xavier/He initialization, and more to improve the models usage. Having Python and TensorFlow as tools, the specialization tackles real-world case studies such as autonomous driving, sign language reading, music generation, computer vision, speech recognition and natural language processing.

Faculty of Engineering of the University of Porto

Porto, Portugal

MASTER IN INFORMATICS AND COMPUTATION ENGINEERING

2009 - 2014

· Master thesis explored the usage of biofeedback data to predict players' affective reaction. These predictive models were then used to aid game developers achieve optimal gameplay experiences. Full Paper approved at: Iberian Conference on Information Systems and Technologies (CISTI 2014), International Conference on Intelligent Agent Technology (IAT 2014) and the Tenth Annual Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Interactive Digital Entertainment (AIIDE'14).